Subtitles downloaded from www.OpenSubtitles.org
InSUBs
Quality is irreplaceable!
Translation Kid Hugo
Good morning.
Finally got you!
Not the first time
stealing, right?
Empty your pockets.
You're hurting me!
Empty pockets
or call the guard!
What are you doing
with all this?
- Empty the other.
- There's nothing in it.
Call the guard!
Ghosts.
You drew this?
It was you who designed it?
Where stole it?
Do not steal.
A thief and a liar.
Get out of here.
- Give me my book!
- No longer yours, is mine!
- No!
- So tell me who drew!
Get lost you thief!
Why are you still here?
Go away!
You hear that?
Then go back!
Excuse me! Excuse me!
Excuse me!
Police passing by!
What?
Nothing to see here.
Stop that boy!
Hey! Stop!
[da..]!
Stop the train! Stop!
Help!
Stop the train!
Make it stop!
Sorry, sorry!
No, no!
The Invention of Hugo Cabret
I know it's there.
What is your name?
Hugo. Hugo Cabret.
Stay away from me
Hugo Cabret.
Or I'll take you to the police station
station,
put him in prison
where you will not leave,
not going to school
will never marry, have children,
to pick up stuff
they do not own.
Give me back my notebook.
I'll take your book to
home and burn it.
- You can not burn it!
- And who's gonna stop me?
How are you?
- Very angry.
- Why?
A boy ...
Who are you?
His grandfather stole my book.
You need to take back
before it burns.
Papa George is my grandfather!
And not a thief, that is you!
You are nothing but
an immoral.
- You need to go.
- I'm not going without my notebook.
Why do you need him?
I can not tell.
It's a secret?
- It is.
- Great, I love secrets!
- Tell me what it is.
- No!
If you do not tell me, go away.
Not without my book!
We'll be in trouble.
Go home!
Okay, do not let
burn the book.
Now go away!
What is this?
- It's called 'robot'.
- A robot?
Was abandoned
in the attic of the museum.
What does it do?
He is like a
music box.
It's more complicated
I've seen ... so far.
It can write.
But it was not done
in London.
And where is it?
And Coventry, but
was built in London.
Magic used machines as well
when I was little.
Some walked,
others sang,
but the secret was always
the heart. Look at that.
- Can we fix it?
- I do not know, Hugo.
He is very rusty.
Find the right parts
will be very difficult.
But it is clear that
let's fix it.
We are clockmakers, is not it?
But I must finish my
work in the shop and museum.
You understand.
Hold carefully.
Perfect.
You see this?
Another complication.
Another mystery.
This makes you happy?
A lock of the form
of heart.
Unfortunately,
we do not have the key.
I fixed the gears ...
Uncle Claude?
There was a fire.
His father is dead.
Pack your bags, fast.
You will live with me.
Quick!
You will be my apprentice, and will
live with me at the station.
I will teach you
to take care of everything.
These apartments are
made inside the station.
All forgotten
we're here.
His bed is in the corner.
Get some sleep.
We will start work at 5am.
What about school?
No more school!
You will not have time for it
when working.
Hugo ...
you would be in the
orphanage without me.
Time ... Time is ...
60 seconds of one minute.
Gives 1 hour 60 minutes.
Timing is everything.
Time, time ...
Stop!
Stop it!
No, no, no!
Good day!
Good morning, sir,
I help you?
I thought I would see today.
I need my notebook.
Why do you need?
To help me fix
one thing.
Go away.
Please, go away.
Wait!
Sorry, I ...
Are you crying?
- No.
- Stand still.
Pronto. There is nothing
wrong with crying.
Sydney Carton cries,
and Heathcliff.
I can clean.
I need to talk with you.
It is very important, but ...
But not here.
We are very ...
exposed.
- Come on.
- Where are we going?
The most wonderful place
the world.
It's like Neverland
or Treasure Island.
You'll like it.
Isabelle ...
I present to you
Mr. Hugo Cabret,
an old and dear friend.
Mr. Cabret.
Hello
Thanks for that.
I'm not even half
than David Copperfield does.
- Photography?
- That corner.
- Upper shelf.
- Thank you.
- Listen, what is so important?
- He still has his notebook.
He did not burn,
was a trick.
- Why?
- I do not know.
Just know that the book
left very upset.
He and Mama were Jeanne
up late talking.
I think he cried.
Why are you helping me?
Because it can be
an adventure!
And I never had one like that.
Off the books, at least.
And I think
will be quite ...
Illegal!
Okay.
Incidentally, my name is Isabelle.
Whether a book?
Monsieur Labisse lends me,
It also lends to you.
Do not like books?
I like it.
My father and I read
many stories together.
Come on.
How do I recover
my notebook?
I think you should
face it.
And do not talk that talk.
I will help you as you can.
Be strong for us.
Go away.
Fix it.
Get that fixed.
I know who has stolen
tools.
Use those that have not robbed.
Give me back the book.
You have talent.
If I prove that it is
more than a thief,
- Have your notebook back.
- How?
Work here to pay
stole everything.
And I'll decide when to return
the notebook, if you return.
- I already have work.
- Stealing is not working.
I have a different job.
I'll come when you can.
You start tomorrow.
Go away.
I'll start now.
That is not, is another.
It is your letter?
Where is it?
Little Man ...
- He fled the orphanage, right?
- Do not run away!
You have parents?
No!
Excellent, then place
is at the orphanage, right?
Why were you looking
the lunch that man?
It was his? Age?
Here is Gustav talking.
Yes, sir, not always.
This time it was stolen
and invasion.
His hand was encroaching
the paper bag
to remove its contents.
What had in
bag? A loaf of bread.
Be quiet!
Nobody sent
do that crimezinho
with their dirty little hands.
Of course I'm not talking
with you. I respect him.
There was a comment
about his wife?
This is absurd.
I heard no rumor.
I did not know that. With
sure she will return.
Come on!
I was stealing a loaf of bread!
Your thief!
I am sorry for his wife.
You can not do
nothing about ...
Come here!
Pig!
What? I do not know what to do.
Of course it's your fault.
Who else?
Of course it's yours. When
were close last?
- Last year?
- I think not.
Very suspicious.
If you see her, please ...
Do you really want her back?
Yes, I do. I love her dearly.
Robin Hood, I saw the movie.
With Douglas Fairbanks.
- Have you seen?
- I've never seen a movie.
- What?
- Is not it strange?
You've never seen
a movie? Nunquinha?
Pope leaves no Georges.
He is very strict.
I love movies.
My father took me
on my birthday.
Hugo ...
his father died?
I do not want to talk about it.
Isabel.
Want an adventure?
[dumb] FILM FESTIVAL
We'll be in trouble.
I thought I wanted adventure.
As the two mice
get in here?
I never
see them here!
Why George Pope
do not let it go to the movies?
I do not know, he never
said nothing.
My father did not leave.
What happened to him?
He died,
when I was little.
Papa and Mama Jeanne Georges
are my [vain use]parents.
They are very
with all legal ...
least in movies.
My father took me
the movies all the time.
He told me about
the first one he saw.
He entered a dark room
and, on the screen, saw a rocket fly
to the eye of the moon
That's right.
He took me to the movies
at midday.
The film was our
special place.
It was where I could see something.
I never met my mother as well.
You think much of him, right?
All the time.
Hugo ...
Where do you live?
There.
My uncle taught me
to operate all
I continue to do so.
Perhaps he will return one day.
??But I doubt it.
Not afraid
anyone knows?
Not while watches
work and nobody sees me.
Act naturally.
- What?
- Walk, act naturally.
How am I doing now?
You, stop!
Come here.
- Good morning, Monsieur.
- Where are your parents?
I live with Papa Georges,
the workshop.
You should now
have seen me there.
And this is my cousin
the field. Hugo.
You need to forgive him.
It is small mind.
It is rather stupid.
Poor baby.
It seems that Maximilian
do not like your clothes.
He is troubled
with his physiognomy.
He's angry
with his face.
Why does not he like
of his face?
Perhaps it makes sense
the smell of my cat.
- Cat?
- Yes
Christina Rossetti.
Is the name of a poet.
Want to hear?
My heart is a
Bird singing
Whose nest is a
offspring dewy
My heart is an apple tree
Bending the trunk
fruit weight
Enough, I've had poetry
enough today.
Well, take good care of
Christina ...
- Rossetti.
- It's one of my favorites.
I know it's Rossetti.
But the season is not
place for poetry.
Here is the place to go
and out of trains.
And working in workshops.
Understood?
- Yes, sir.
- Be careful where you walk.
Carry on.
[idiot]!
Since I saved his life.
Why do not I see your muquifo?
- My what?
- Where do you live. Your home.
I gotta go, I
things to do.
Wait! Have you seen my house
I can not see her?
I'm your only friend!
It is not.
Being enigmatic
does not suit you.
What are you up to?
I have to go,
you should not even be here.
Hugo!
Where did you get that?
- It will not matter.
- I need her.
- For what?
- I have to.
Only if you tell me why.
Come on.
Incredible!
It's like Jean Valjean.
This is fantastic.
What is this?
It's a robot.
My father was fixing
before dying.
Why is my key fit
his father's machine?
He looks sad.
I think he's waiting.
For what?
To work again.
This is not what it
supposed to do?
What happens if I connect it?
I do not know.
What is the problem?
I know that's silly.
But I think we have
a message from my father.
I am a fool
because he thought he could fix it!
It's broken!
Always broke!
Hugo does not have to
look like, you can fix it.
You do not understand.
I thought ...
I thought if I could fix it,
would not be so alone.
Hugo ...
Hugo, look!
Not finished yet!
He does not write,
it draws!
It's the movie
My father watched.
Georges M li s?
Is the name of Papa Georges.
Why does your machine
parent sign it?
I do not know.
Thank you.
It was a message from my father.
Now we need to find
the meaning.
Isabelle?
Mama Jeanne, yes.
We need to talk.
This is Hugo Cabret.
Good evening, ma'am.
Manners for a thief.
I am not a thief.
What's going on, Isabelle?
It is a very long history.
Remember a few weeks ago ...
Wait!
Poor ...
Where did you get this?
You will call me
a liar.
No, boy.
A robot designed.
You're with him?
My father found
the museum.
Nobody wanted him.
We fix it.
But need to ...
My key.
I gave you?
No, no, mama ...
Take it! I can not
see it now.
Do not let George Pope
see it.
Tell us what's going on.
It does not matter!
Let's forget it.
My father and I work
hard to fix it.
That was all
I had left it.
I need to know
what it means.
Please.
You're too young to
understand some things.
You should not
knowing sadness.
- Is the Pope Georges.
- He can not see it here.
Stay silent.
I'll find a way
to take him upstairs.
Do not want to hear a peep.
She looked at the closet.
I've tried the notebook there.
I'll look again.
Keep an eye out.
Great.
I'll find a way
to take him upstairs.
Do not want to hear a peep.
She looked at the closet.
I've tried the notebook there.
I'll look again.
Keep an eye out.
Great.
Here!
We need to investigate.
Let me, I'm taller.
Back from the dead ...
Stop! It's your job!
It is not! It is the job
a broken toy!
I trusted you.
This is how you thank me?
You are cruel.
Cruel!
I better get back.
Thank you ...
the film today.
It was a gift.
Excuse me, I ...
Do you know this book?
My father and I read together.
This was for my grandson.
But now I think is
to you, sir. Cabret.
Would you like another cup?
Not yet, soon.
Everything must happen
in due course.
If I knew how,
would have done.
Gustav, be brave.
Say 'hello' to her.
Give me your best smile.
Your best smile!
It's beautiful.
Radiant!
Thank you.
Mademoiselle Lisette,
a good night to you.
You also inspector.
Yes ..
These roses are beautiful.
Thank you. They are of Bordeaux.
They come on the night train,
then they are very fresh.
Bordeaux has clean fields.
No past ...
No limitations ...
Carts everywhere.
A perfect place.
They smell?
The flowers smell?
Yes, they did. Please.
I was wounded in the war
and will never be cured.
Good evening, mademoiselle.
I lost my brother.
Where?
Verdun.
Good evening, sir. Inspector.
Good evening,
Mademoiselle Lisette.
The Library
Film Academy.
How?
The Library
Film Academy.
There you will find everything
you want to know about movies.
Second floor,
fourth row, section 3 ...
and top shelf.
The Invention of Dreams.
Ren Tabard.
The story of the first
movies.
'In 1995, one of the first
films shown
was called 'A Train
Arriving at the station, '
that was nothing but
than a train coming.
As the train sped
toward the screen,
the crowd shouted.
Because they thought
would be hit.
No one had ever seen
nothing like that. '
'No one had ever seen
'So that movie
turned into something else,
when the first
filmmakers discovered
they could use the new media
to tell stories. '
'The filmmaker Georges Melies
was one of the first
to realize
films that had the power
dreams of playing. '
'The great pioneer of
died in cinema ...
the Great War. '
He died?
- During the Great War?
- They are interested in M li s?
We are.
Is allowed.
Really?
He is my [vain use]father. It is
very much alive. Thank you.
But this is not possible.
Yes, sir,
believe me.
Why should I
believe?
Because ...
Because it's true.
M li s is alive?
Come with me.
Her [vain use]father
a passion of mine.
He was a great filmmaker.
This is it working
in the studio.
And this is a flyer
Part of it.
This is the mysterious clock,
made by his mentor,
Hubert Hudain.
And this is a
the camera from him.
- It was magic?
- Yes, got on stage.
How it started
making films?
I do not know.
See how happy he was.
Teacher Tabard,
you want
you know it?
See, I already knew.
My brother worked
building sets for him.
One day he took me
to visit the studio.
It was like a dream.
Every place
was made of glass.
That gave the necessary light
for the film,
but for me it was a
enchanted castle.
A palace made of glass.
You have a lobster in front ...
If you ever wonder
where they come from your dreams,
look around.
Here is where they are made.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the music will start.
Fish and lobsters
in position.
Mermaids in position. Action!
He came to do
more than 500 films.
It was very popular
at that time.
But why stop?
Until today, I believe that
he died in the war.
How many others.
We watch
some films?
I wish so,
but time does not
was generous with them.
This is the only
who survived.
Hundreds, only one.
Still ...
is a work of art.
We have to show the movie
Pope Georges.
So he will see
that has not been forgotten.
Must not tell
Mama Jeanne?
No one should be surprised,
like a magic trick.
We need to have class.
Very well.
Monsieur Claude?
It's up there?
It is you, monsieur Claude?
Still
drunk in this life?
You can not
or hold a bottle, right?
Are you listening?
He's drunk?
He's drunk, no?
You [idiot]!
It could have hit
a child.
Monsieur gave me Labisse
a book.
He always does that.
Send books for good
home. That is what he says.
He has a purpose.
How so?
Everything has a purpose
to the machines.
Clocks tell the time,
trains carry you.
They do
they should do.
As Monsieur Labisse.
Perhaps for this reason that machines
broken make me sad.
They are not
what to do.
Maybe it's the same
with people.
If you lose your way,
is like breaking.
As Papa Georges.
Maybe we can
fix it.
This is your purpose?
Fix things?
I do not know.
It was what my father did.
I wonder what is
my purpose.
I do not know.
Maybe if I knew
my parents,
I know.
Come with me.
Soon after my father died,
I came here a lot.
I imagined that the world
was a huge machine.
Machines do not have
with extra parts.
They always come
with the exact amount.
If the world
is a single machine,
I could not be
an extra part,
I have a reason
to be here.
Then you also have.
Go back.
I'll bring Tabard
tomorrow at 19h.
Do not speak.
Are you sure?
Not a lot.
But I think
is the only way ...
To fix it.
Cabret AND CHILDREN
Watchmaker
Stop the train!
It has a kid on track!
Come on!
Get out!
It is an employee
maintenance, ma'am.
In the Seine?
Dead. Are you sure?
No, he had relatives.
Thanks, I'll pick up
his belongings. Thank you.
If he is dead,
who has repaired
clocks?
- Good evening.
- This way, sir.
I got it.
What a surprise! Get in!
Isabelle, what is it?
Do not get mad, mama.
This young
is not welcome here.
We found
Who is George Pope.
I'm sorry, ma'am.
I thought I was waiting for us.
I'm going
and only come back if you ask.
Please speak low.
Georges is sleeping,
not been well since ...
- Mama, do not go away.
- No disrespect, ma'am,
but if not a good time
to find it,
please
let me express
gratitude to such
I have to her husband.
When I was young
I saw all his films.
They have inspired me.
Her husband
is a great artist.
I am very happy that remember
of his films with so much love.
But he is too frail.
It hurts him
remembering the past.
So I leave you, lady.
Forgive me for saying this ...
You look so lovely now
as it was in the movies.
Mama?
You were in the movies?
She appeared
in almost everyone.
You were an actress?
It was a long time.
It was another time.
I was someone else.
I would like to rediscover
this person?
We have a movie.
One of the films of Georges?
It is not possible
they were.
Can I show you.
Please! Please, mama!
Observe silence.
You were an actress, really!
It's awesome!
It was not so. It was not
a star like today.
But we had fun.
Lady M li s.
It has color!
Of course! The paint film.
The hand. Frame by frame.
Are you, Mama!
Yes.
Wonderful.
You were beautiful.
She still is.
I recognize the sound
a projector
anywhere.
Georges ...
You tried to forget the past
for a long time ...
But that only you
brought sadness.
Maybe it's time
to remember.
You know what?
I want to.
Like you,
I loved
fix things.
I started as a magician.
Mama Jeanne
was my assistant.
We did very successfully,
filled the theater.
I was always surrounded
machines in my workshop,
where I invented
new illusions.
Once I built a robot.
It was a particular treasure
I put in my soul.
One night, me and Mama Jeanne
went to visit a traveling circus.
We were passing through the stage
when I noticed something wrong.
Something strange. Wonderful.
The Lumi re brothers had
invented the cinema.
I fell in love
for that invention.
It seemed a new type
of magic.
I asked the brothers
I sold a camera,
but they refused,
because they did not see
future in cinema.
In the end, build
my own camera,
with parts that had
left of the robot.
I needed to be part
this new wonder.
We risk everything
sell the theater and everything else
we build up our
own film studio.
It was a great invention.
I wrote, planned, directed
and worked on hundreds
of films.
Action
Stop, stop, stop!
Give me ten minutes,
will be okay.
Here, here.
If you pull the lever
left, it will work.
Great, great!
Go back to your positions!
Action!
Action! Action!
Stay tuned! Attack!
Attacking and killing!
That, move.
Do the choreography.
One, 3, 2, 1 ...
It was great.
Do not move, people.
Come on, folks.
Action!
Magic tricks and illusions
were my specialty.
The world of imagination.
My beautiful wife
was my muse.
My Star.
And we could not be
happier.
Action!
We never
would end ...
But then came the war.
And youth
came to an end.
The world did not have time
for magic tricks.
The soldiers had seen
much reality
they were bored
with my movies.
Tastes have changed,
but I have not changed with them.
Nobody else
I wanted my films.
So I could not
pay the actors
or continue with the business.
So my castle
enchanted collapsed.
Everything was lost.
One night, in desperation,
I burned all the clothes
and scenarios.
I was forced to sell
my films to a company
the melting
to chemicals,
that were used
to make high heels.
With the money left,
opened the workshop of toys,
and that was where I was.
Just could not destroy
my dear robot,
so I gave it to a museum
to give him a home.
But do not put
on display.
Then he burned the museum
and everything is gone.
All I had was gone,
now only ashes remained.
My life has taught me a lesson,
but I wanted to learn.
Happy endings only happen
in the movies.
I'll be back!
Do not panic!
What does he have?
My dear ...
Gentlemen.
Let me tell you
what happened.
What happened?
Mr. know. Claude?
He was found dead.
- No!
- Monsieur Claude?
So he may not continue
working on the clock.
You came back!
- Hi
- Hello
Mr.. Claude is dead.
What? Why?
What happened to him?
They found his body
the Seine.
It seems that there is
a few months ago.
I would not say that ...
Yes, he was a drunk!
Go away ...
Let me go!
- He thought he was going to fool me!
- Let go of me!
Please help me!
Please!
He's winding me
too long!
Drop the boy!
- Give me a break!
- I need to go!
Only when their parents
you seek!
I have no parents!
Then go to the orphanage!
Will learn some
things there. I've learned.
How to obey orders,
how to keep secrets.
How to Survive
no family.
Because nobody
need it.
The headquarters, please.
Yes, it's me again.
Another orphan.
It was a full week.
Invasion, robbery,
theft, roam,
play, eat ...
It's irrelevant!
Send someone to fetch him.
How are you?
She returned?
Do you think is yours?
Excellent!
You will find
in a few months.
Something else?
I'll try to go. I do not plan
well in advance.
Are you sure?
Well, I do not know what to do
with this ...
Wait a minute!
Get it!
Excuse me!
Out of the way!
It does not have to
escape, boy!
307, 308, 309 ...
He went to
other hand, come on!
Get out of my way!
Gotcha!
There's a boy!
Stop the train!
Back! Back!
What were you thinking?
Are you hurt?
Come on!
Excuse me!
- The orphanage will take care of you.
- I do not live there.
So where do you live?
Have to live somewhere.
Hear me, please!
You do not understand!
You need to let me go!
I do not understand
why my father died.
Why am I lonely.
This is my only chance
to work.
You should understand!
I understand!
I understand.
Monsieur ...
This boy belongs to me.
Sorry, it broke.
There is no!
It works perfectly!
And I'm proud
of welcome
the celebration of life and work
Georges M li s.
For years, most
of his films
appeared to have been lost.
Mr. himself. M li s
believed that,
but we begin a search,
a safe, private collections
cellars and catacombs.
Our work was rewarded
with old negatives,
boxes of pictures
and suitcases full of movies,
we can save.
Now we have over 80 movies
Georges M li s.
Tonight, their creator,
and the new member of the academy,
is here to share them
with you.
Ladies and gentlemen, I ...
I am here in front
you today
because of a girl
very brave.
He saw a broken machine
and, against all odds,
he fixed it.
It was the magic trick
kinder
I've seen.
And now ...
My friends,
I call them so,
as they really are.
Magi.
Sirens.
Travelers. Adventurers.
Magicians.
Come dream with me.
The study of the history of cinema
should start with that.
With photography.
Canine Socialization ...
Smile, honey.
I can not remember how.
See, now it works
perfectly.
One day, I met a boy
named Hugo Cabret.
He lived in
a train station.
Why did he live there?
You must be wondering.
It's about this
this book will be.
As this young individual
sought by both
secret message from his father.
And as that message
returned home.
www.insubs.com